Don't bother.
没必要了
He's dead.
他已经死了
You're dead too.
你也死了
The fire isn't.
火还没灭
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==- 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第22集
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 豪斯医生  第八季第22集
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：ID 校对：ID 时间轴：绿
-=破烂熊字幕组=- 翻译：墨墨挥泪送房叔 FF完美告别 校对：代叔叔送大叔 时间轴：小绿快去补课
You might want to get up and start heading for the exit signs.
你还不赶紧站起来去找安全出口
For all I know, I already am up.
据我所知 我已经起来了
More interesting question is why would I hallucinate
更有趣的问题是 我为什么会在幻觉中看到
an ex-employee who I last saw with a self-inflicted gunshot wound,
一个饮弹自尽的前下属
as opposed to someone more...
而不是其他那些...
busty?
胸部更有料的?
Care to explain why you're here? The dead guy.
- 能给解释下 你为什么会出现在这里吗? - 这个死掉的人
Who is he?
他是谁?
How'd you meet him?
你是怎么遇到他的?
I was in a car accident last month.
上个月我发生了一场车祸
I won a swimming trophy in high school.
我高中时得过游泳冠军呢
Your turn.
该你了
I-I ran out of pain medication. I got an orbital fracture.
我的止痛药没有了 我的眶骨骨折了
It's just taking ages to heal. Take off your shirt.
- 过了这么多天也不见好 - 把衬衫脱掉
My eye's up here.
可我的眼睛在这儿呢
Orbital fracture means your face went into the windshield,
眶骨骨折说明你的脸撞到了挡风玻璃上
which means your chest went into the steering wheel.
也就是说你的胸部撞到了方向盘上
Painkillers can suppress heart rate, so unless you want me to kill you,
止痛药会减缓你的心率 所以除非你想让我杀死你
take off your shirt, let me do a heart exam.
否则就把衬衫脱了 让我给你检查下心脏功能
I also wanted to see the ring of burns
我还想看看你锁骨
around your collarbone.
周围那一圈烧伤的痕迹
How'd you know?
你怎么知道的?
The codeine allergy you told the nurse about.
你之前告诉护士说你对可待因过敏
That's shorthand for "give me the strong stuff," which matches your seen-better-days-
那是"给我开强效止痛药"的简写 这和你那件"风光不再
because-my-life- fell-apart suit.
因为我的人生四分五裂"的西服正好匹配
The two old burns on your fingers mean you tend to nod off with a cigarette in your hand.
你手指上两处旧烧伤 意味着你手里拿烟的时候犯困了
No reason you shouldn't do that with one in your mouth.
嘴里明明叼着一根烟 没理由不这样做啊
May all your doctors be stupid.
愿你所有的医生都是蠢货
Hold on a second.
等等
That bruising around your belly button.
你肚脐周围的瘀伤
Well, you might get some fun drugs
这下你终于能拿到止痛药了
Cullen's sign.
出现卡伦氏征
But the ultrasound showed air as well as blood.
但超声波显示呼吸和循环系统都没有问题
Now, I know what you're thinking. Hemorrhagic pancreatitis.
我知道你在想什么 出血性胰腺炎
But I also know what I'm thinking.
但我也知道我在想些什么
Doesn't explain the pneuomoperitoneum.
这无法解释他的气腹
You took a new case? You ran tests yourself?
- 你接了一个新病例? - 你自己给病人做的检查?
I saw the chance to help someone in need, and I instinctively--
我看到了一个帮助他人的机会 于是我本能地...
oh, no, wait, that was someone else's instinct. Wilson is dying.
- 哦 等等 那是别人的本能 - Wilson要死了
Your parole officer is probably on his way here right now.
你的假释官可能正在来这儿的路上
How are you possibly in a good mood?
你怎么可能还有这样的好心情呢?
Did you never see Dead Poets Society? Carpe diem.
你难道没看过"死亡诗社"吗? 及时行乐啊
Air in his abdomen could mean
他腹腔中的空气可能意味着...
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
吧啦吧啦吧啦吧啦吧啦
But blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
但是 吧啦吧啦吧啦吧啦吧啦
Blah. Blah, blah.
吧啦吧啦吧啦
Nobody cares about the medicine. It was perforated ulcer.
没人在乎到底是什么病 其实是穿孔性溃疡
Laparotomy to find the hole in his tummy and close it up.
做个开腹手术找到他胃上的洞 缝上就好了
You didn't answer the team's question.
你没有回答你团队的问题
Which is weird, because normally, when I talk to my own employees,
这很奇怪 因为通常来说 在我和我自己的下属谈话时
I'm under oath and hooked up to a lie detector.
我都先发誓 再连上个测谎仪
You were looking at six months of prison instead of five months of Wilson.
你要面对的是六个月的监禁 而不是Wilson仅剩五个月的生命
Why happy? Obviously I had a plan.
- 你为什么要高兴呢? - 很显然我有计划了
Obviously, obviously you had a plan.
很显然 你显然有计划了
The more interesting question is why you didn't tell the team.
更有趣的问题是你为什么没有告诉你的团队呢
I think it's because part of you knew from the start that the plan wouldn't work.
我想是因为你从开始就知道这个计划不会成功的
- I need a meeting. - I'm busy. Call my office.
- 我得跟你谈谈 - 我很忙 给我办公室打电话
Yes...
好吧...
because wobbly tables don't just unwobble themselves.
因为晃动的桌子不会自己就突然不晃了
I need a meeting. Thanks for fitting me in.
我得跟你谈谈 谢谢你抽空接待我
My team has eight urgent, life-or-death cases
我的团队接到了八个紧急的 生死相关的病例
that they've been waiting for me to accept or reject.
他们在等着我说是接受还是拒绝呢
When is that not true?
只不过不是真的?
Well, right now, for one.
好吧 现在就一个
But tell my parole board that I'm taking all eight...
但是跟我假释委员会说我八个病案都接了...
that no one else can crack them, that you need me here for the next five months
而且除了我没人能治好他们 你之后的五个月都需要我在这
or eight people will die.
否则这八个人就死定了
You're asking me to perjure myself.
你这是让我作伪证
It's a tiny, white lie.
这不过是一个小小的善意的谎言
No offense.
无意冒犯
Especially since, from what I hear, nothing black is tiny.
尤其是自从我听说 黑人之事无小事
Except your penis, I guess.
当然我猜 除了你的小鸡鸡
You really think I wanted to cave in that ceiling?
你以为我真的想在天花板上弄个洞出来吗?
It was a prank that went wrong.
那是恶作剧玩过火了
Dock my pay, sue me--
扣我工资 起诉我...
Felony vandalism should have added another year or two to your sentence.
恶意破坏公物是重罪 本应再给你加一到两年刑期的
It's a miracle the parole board agreed to six months.
假释委员会同意只让你服刑六个月已经是奇迹了
I will go to jail, eventually.
我最后肯定是会进监狱的
I will pay the price.
我会付出我应付的代价
I just rather that Wilson didn't.
我只是希望Wilson不要跟着受罪
Come on, be a friend.
求你了 朋友一场嘛
Okay.
好吧
But whatever cases you have, you have to take them all.
但不管你碰到什么病案 你都要接下来
"Be a friend"?
"朋友一场"?
How many fingers am I holding up?
我伸出了几个手指?
Of course you know it's three, because you know everything I know.
你当然知道是三个 因为你知道我知道的一切
Everything my smack-addled brain can remember,
我混沌的大脑能记起的一切
including that I actually said, "be a friend."
包括我说过的 "朋友一场"
My point wasn't that you said it.
我的重点不是你说了这句话
My point was, once again, why?
我的重点是 你为什么要这么说?
I think it's because part of you knew you were gonna need a friend.
我想是因为你心里知道 你是需要一个朋友的
Part of you knew the plan,
而你心里也知道 那个计划即使执行了 也不会成功的
And right now, I'm curious about why you're sitting on the ground
而现在 我很好奇你为什么还坐在地上
instead of heading for the door.
而不是朝门口走去
Guess we figured out why you're seeing me,
我想我们大概知道了你为什么会看到我
your suicidal friend.
你自杀身亡的朋友
He'll call you twice a day.
他会给你一天打两次电话
Then his wife will call you twice a day to make sure she understands what he told her you told him,
然后他妻子就会给你一天打两次电话 以确保她理解 他转述给她你说过的话
which she won't because he didn't.
但她不会给你打 因为他不会告诉她的
Maybe you want to give this one to Connors.
也许你该把这个转给Connors
Where's House? Don't know, don't care.
- House去哪了? - 不知道 也不在乎
Working.
我在工作呢
Excuse me.
失陪一下
No one has seen or heard from him since two nights ago.
自从两天前 就没人有他的消息了
I'm sure he's enjoying himself.
我很肯定他正逍遥快活着呢
Last time he went to prison, he maxed out his credit cards.
上次他进监狱时 他刷爆了他的信用卡
Last time he went to prison,
上次他进监狱时
he thought he had you waiting for him.
他知道有你会等他出来
You think he could've done something stupid?
你觉得他会做傻事?
I think stupid is our best-case scenario.
我觉得他做傻事还算最好的了
Why do you want to kill yourself?
你为什么想要自杀呢?
Well, here's a reason.
我告诉你原因
I can't even get stoned without some annoying jerk
没有那个认为我需要被深度分析的
deciding I need to be deeply analyzed.
讨人厌的混蛋 我连嗑药的劲头都没有
Isn't this just an incredibly simple calculation?
这难道不就是个简单的算数问题吗?
I'm going to jail, losing my job, losing my best friend.
我要进监狱了 要失去我的工作 失去我最好的朋友
Do I need more?
我还需要更多的理由吗?
You think that's the sum total of who you are? A doctor? A friend to Wilson?
你觉得这加起来就构成了你的整个人生吗? 一位医生? Wilson的朋友?
I'm also a tremendous baritone.
我还是一名相当厉害的男中音歌手
Now go away.
现在离我远点儿
Even with your subconscious, you're evasive.
就算在你的潜意识里 你还是在逃避
Death's not interesting.
死亡是无趣的
You exist for what's interesting.
你的存在是为了那些有趣的东西
Puzzles, ideas, analysis.
谜题 想法 分析
Death is the opposite of a cool puzzle.
死亡是错综复杂的谜题的对立面
It's eternal nothingness.
死亡是永恒的虚无
But you don't find life interesting anymore.
但是你觉得人生不再有趣了
Stop being an idiot.
别犯傻了
Can I have Kutner back, please? How much pathetic wallowing do I have to sit through?
- 我能让Kutner回来吗? - 我要听你自怨自艾到什么时候?
How are things in hell? Is the humidity the big issue?
地狱里怎么样? 湿气是不是太重了?
What happened next with the guy's medical case?
这个人的病后来怎样了?
Why? Exactly.
- 你为什么要知道? - 没错
Why am I, meaning you,
为什么我 也就是你自己
still obsessing about this case?
对这个病例如此执着?
Obviously we think it's relevant to why we're still sitting on the floor of a burning building.
显然我们认为这和我们还 坐在一栋着火的楼房里面有关系
There was a code.
出现了一个暗示
Gotta be a clot in his lungs.
他肺里肯定有血栓
We need to get him to an O.R. No time. His O-2 stats are falling.
- 我们得把他送进手术室 - 没时间了 他的氧饱和度正在下降
We have to suck it out here. Bedside embolectomy.
我们得在这把它吸出来 病床血栓切除术
Float a catheter through his heart and his oxygenation will get even worse.
把管子插进他的心脏里 会让他体内的氧气越来越少的
He'll die before we can finish the procedure.
在我们完成手术前他就会没命的
House, we need a call here.
House 我们需要赶紧做出决定
What are you doing? What did you give him?
你在干什么? 你给他注射了什么?
Five, four...
五 四...
three, two...
三 二...
Naloxone.
纳洛酮 (吗啡拮抗药)
We should've got suspicious when his visiting cousin
我们在他表弟以"Tar H. Horse先生"的名字探访登记时 就该起疑了
Heroin caused the respiratory distress.
海洛因引起了呼吸困难
The naloxone turned off the receptors, caused your distress.
纳洛酮使受体失活 引发了你的痛苦
I'm not gonna stop doing drugs!
我才不要戒毒!
It's reality that sucks!
现实苦不堪言!
You're saying I'm lying... to my subconscious?
你是说我对我的潜意识说谎了?
People do it all the time. And like it or not, you are a person.
人们常会如此 不管你喜不喜欢 你也是人
He said every one of those things. But not then and not like that.
- 这些他都说过 - 但当时不是 也不像这样
This guy was going nuts from the naloxone.
这个人因为纳洛酮差点儿疯了
He couldn't be rational if you wanted him to be, which you did.
只要你想 他也可以通情达理的 而你就是这么做的
Why? I compressed the story a little--
- 为什么? - 我把故事压缩了一点儿...
Context matters.
上下文很重要的
You never talk to patients for non-diagnostic reasons,
你从来不会为了与诊断无关的原因去和病人谈话
but this guy...
但是这个人...
Feeling better?
感觉好点了吗?
I'm not gonna stop doing drugs.
我不会去戒毒的
You were a stockbroker.
你是个股票经纪人
Son of a stockbroker.
你父亲也是股票经纪人
- Married, children. - I was miserable.
- 你结婚了 有孩子了 - 我很痛苦
Well, you say you were miserable
好吧 你说你很痛苦
because you need to rationalize screwing it up.
是因为你需要让自己搞砸一切变得合理化
Except I didn't.
可是我没有
I mean, I-I did.
我是说或 我确实搞砸了
But I'm not miserable. Not anymore.
但我不痛苦 再也不了
I had a ski injury
我之前滑雪受伤了
and painkillers weren't enough,
止痛药不足以缓解我的痛苦
and a friend of mine gave me some heroin.
一个朋友给了我一些海洛因
The second it entered my veins,
它进入我血管的那一刻
it was like God had taken over my body.
就如同上帝接管了我的身体
It was like there was no more pain
就好像我的生活还有别人的生活
or unhappiness in my life or anybody else's.
再也没有痛苦和悲伤了
But then you lost everything.
但之后你失去了一切
Everything wasn't enough.
一切是远远不够的
Because it's reality that sucks.
因为现实苦不堪言
Are you arguing that he's a good role model?
你在试图说明他是一个优秀的道德楷模吗?
- He's happy. - He's dead.
- 他是快乐的 - 可他死了
You heard what you wanted to hear.
你听到的是你想要听到的
The more interesting question--
更有趣的问题是...
always--is why you wanted to hear it.
一直都是 你为什么想要听到这些话
You're stealing this guy's oxygen?
你在偷这个人的氧气?
There's oxygen everywhere.
氧气到处都是啊
You passed on all your cases, reassigned them to other doctors.
你推掉了你所有的病案 转手给了其他医生
They weren't interesting.
因为不好玩
They were my reason for getting your sentence delayed!
可这样我才能让你的服刑时间推后
Yeah, well, I guess you'll have to tell the parole board something else.
好吧 我想你得跟假释委员会再说个别的理由了
Maybe that I was in the O.R.
也许那天我在手术室里
the entire day the ceiling collapsed, so I couldn't have caused the plumbing problem.
天花板坍塌的那天一整天都在 所以我没空去堵下水管
- You set me up. - Not really.
- 你这是在给我下套 - 不尽然
You were going to basically perjure yourself so that I could delay jail time.
本来是你去作伪证好 让我可以延后坐牢时间
Doesn't it make more sense to actually perjure yourself
你做伪证 让我能逃过牢狱之灾 这样不是更合情理吗?
Why are you doing this?
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you risking destroying yourself? There's no risk. I know you.
- 你为什么要冒险毁掉自己? - 没有风险 我了解你
You'll do the honest thing.
你会做正直的事情的
You'll lie.
你会说谎的
No.
不
He's happy.
他很快乐
He's dead.
他死了
You weren't worried. Of course I was worried. My plan fell through.
- 你一点都不担心 - 我当然担心 我的计划失败了
The plan didn't matter.
计划不重要
Your plan to replace that plan didn't matter.
你的候补计划也不重要
Wilson didn't matter. Jail didn't matter.
Wilson不重要 监狱不重要
The only thing that mattered, the only thing that ever mattered,
唯一重要的 一直以来唯一重要的
was the puzzle.
就是谜题
I noticed a slight twitch in his thenar eminence,
我注意到了他拇指底部肌肉的轻微痉挛
which meant...
也就意味着...
You're dying.
你要死了
Because my thumb's a little shaky?
因为我的拇指有些抖?
Plus the thinning in the muscle, plus that speech you gave at Yankee Stadium
加上肌肉萎缩 加上你在扬基体育场发表的讲话
saying you were the luckiest man on the face of the earth.
说你是地球上最幸运的人
Add them up, it means ALS.
所有的症状加起来 意味着你得了肌萎缩性脊髓侧索硬化症
Lou Gehrig's disease?
葛雷克氏症?
You're trapped in your body, you can't move or speak while you just die.
你将受困于你的身体 在你要死的时候你不能动也无法说话
If it makes you feel any better, at this rate, it'll be fast.
如果能让你感觉好点的话 以病情恶化的速度来看 你很快就会死的
You're not symmetrical.
你的症状不是对称出现的
Wait. Now you're standing at the door.
等等 现在你站在门口
What happened in the meantime? And lo, there was a miraculous wonder--
- 这中间发生了什么? - 瞧啊 这是一个伟大的奇迹...
I walked across the room.
我穿过了病房
No, you just skipped over a chunk of conversation.
不 你跳过了一大段谈话
He swore that he would live a better and more selfless life in his remaining time,
他发誓在余下的生命里会成为一个更好更无私的人
blah, blah, blah.
吧啦吧啦吧啦
After two blahs, I'd heard enough.
在两把吧啦之后 我就听够了
I moved to the door.
于是我走到了门口
No, you're avoiding it.
不 你这是在逃避
Do you smell smoke?
你闻到烟的味道了吗?
Fair enough.
好吧
You're not symmetrical.
你的症状不是对称出现的
The veins on your right side are distended.
你的右侧血管膨大
What does that mean? There's a bulge in your superclavicular notch.
- 那意味着什么? - 你的锁骨处有肿大
There's something in there. What?
- 里面有东西 - 什么东西?
Well, I'm not that good a doctor.
我可没有透视眼
Good news: Your case is fascinating.
好消息是 你的病例很有趣
And good news for you: You're gonna live.
而对你来说好消息是 你死不了了
You've inhaled a small branch,
你吸入了一个小树叉
probably while you were realizing that it's all worth it while you were passed out
可能是在你吸毒吸High后晕倒在
on a park bench. Anyone else would have coughed it up,
公园长椅上的时候 别人会咳出来
but 'cause you're a junkie, your cough reflex is suppressed. And it grew?
- 可因为你吸毒 你的咳嗽反射被抑制了 - 现在它长成大树了?
Not unless you also inhaled a chunk of the sun
除非你还吸入了太阳
and a drip-irrigation system, you idiot.
和灌溉系统 你个白痴
It set off an auto-immune reaction, which-- I can't help saying this--
它引发了自体免疫反应 也就是 我不得不说
was the root of all your problems.
你一切问题的根源
You're smiling.
你在微笑
I was, and now I'm not
我有在笑 现在没有
because a moment's fun a few days ago does not trump a friend dying.
因为几天前的快乐一刻抵不上 好朋友要死所带来的悲伤
Yeah, it does, you idiot.
当然可以 你个白痴
'Cause after he's dead, you cry for a while,
因为在他死后 你可以大哭一通
and then you go back to doing what you love.
然后就可以继续做你所热衷的一切了
Every patient that I've had, 70 years from now, they'll all be
我经手的每个病人 70年之后 他们都会像Wilson一样死去
Everybody dies. It's meaningless.
每个人都会死 这一切都毫无意义
When you solve a puzzle, the world makes sense, and everything feels right.
当你解决一个谜题时 整个世界都有意义了 感觉一切都对了
And you'll always have another one, because people always get sick.
而谜题总会出现 因为人们总会生病
It's shallow and it's insignificant, but if you don't give a damn if idiots live,
确实肤浅且毫无意义 但如果你连白痴们是死是活都不在乎
why would you possibly give a damn about shallowness?
怎么可能还会在乎肤浅与否呢
It makes you happy.
它让你快乐
And why would you need more than that?
你干嘛还需要其他更多的呢
Go home.
回家去吧
Foreman!
Foreman!
House would never leave food out here rotting for days.
House从来不会就把吃的东西放在外面让它变馊的
His suitcases are in his closet.
他的箱子也还在衣柜里
If we had handled this differently--
如果我们处理的方式能稍微变一下--
We did the right thing.
我们做得没错
Hello?
喂?
I'll let his accountant know.
好吧 我跟他的会计说一声
House no-showed on a hooker two nights ago.
两晚之前 House放了约好的妓女鸽子
Outgoing calls.
拨出电话
Hooker...
鸡...
me... I didn't pick up.
我...我没接
Chinese place...
中餐外卖...
Wait, wait, wait. Who's that?
等一下 等一下 这个是谁啊?
He called four times. I don't know.
- 他打了四次电话 - 我不知道
It's a total disaster.
真是糟糕透了
Do you have any idea how hard it is to schedule a cable appointment
你知道就我工作的点儿
with the hours that I work? House has been missing for two days.
- 约个上门装有线电视的有多难吗？ - House已经失踪两天了
We know talked to you.
我们知道他跟你谈过
Anything you can tell us about his mental state,
你能提供任何关于他精神状态
or where he was headed-- anything at all--
或者行踪的信息吗? 任何一点信息...
Would be a breach of confidentiality and a violation of the law.
都是违反医护保密协定并且同时触犯法律的
Not if he's a danger to himself or someone else.
如果他对他自己或他人造成危害就不是犯法了
Is this coming out of our 50 minutes? Is this your douche bag group?
- 这会算在我们的50分钟里吗? - 这就是你的混蛋大聚会吗?
Excuse me.
失陪一下
What makes you think he's a danger to himself?
你们为什么觉得他对自己造成危害了?
He hasn't been home, but he didn't take anything with him, not even his cell.
他没回过家 什么东西也没带走 连手机都没拿
You're not saying anything, which means he didn't specifically mention suicide,
你什么都没说 表示他并没有特别提到自杀的打算
but you came out here to talk to us,
但是你跟我们出来说了
so he must have said something that worries you.
又说明他肯定说了什么让你担心的话
There are other ways of reaching oblivion.
想要就此了无烦恼 还有其他的法子
- Vicodin? - He always has his Vicodin.
- 维柯丁? - 他一直都有他的维柯丁在手
There's no reason to call a shr--
如果只是这个的话他没有理由...
his last patient was a heroin addict.
他上一个病人海洛因成瘾
So I guess we're all done here.
我觉得我们这算是说完了吧
The guy's address has gotta be in the file.
那人的地址一定在他的病历里
What about God?
那么上帝呢?
You were leaving, and then you stopped. Why?
你本来要走的 然后又停下了 为什么呢?
Your theory is I'm not leaving, because I believe in God?
于是你的理论就是我不走 是因为我信上帝吗?
What, he's calling me home?
怎么 他还要唤我回家不成?
Maybe falling through that floor was a sign. Maybe that the universe hates you--something.
可能从地板上跌落下来是个征兆 比如整个世界都恨你...什么的
You really don't believe?
你真的不信吗?
Really? Not in some deep crack
真的吗? 哪怕在你头脑
of some remote recess of some dark corner of your mind?
阴暗逼仄的角落里 你也不信吗?
No.
不信
Except that some deep crack of some remote recess of some dark corner
但是我头脑中有些阴暗逼仄的角落
is here telling me-- that's enough.
- 却正在告诉我... - 够了
In a burning building, facing imminent death, that's more than enough.
在燃烧的大楼里面对步步逼近的死亡 这的确已经足够了
Pascal's wager is facile.
帕斯卡尔之赌本就是浅薄的 (帕斯卡尔之赌: 若信神比不信神更有可能获利 那么每个人都应以信神的方式活着)
Saying it's facile is facile.
说它浅薄才是浅薄
Why is it wrong?
它为什么不对呢?
And don't be logical. Be desperate.
别再讲究逻辑了 来点困兽之斗吧
You gotta have something to hold on to.
你必须得有能让你坚持下去的东西
You can't live your life based on something you don't believe.
你不能把你的整个生命建筑在你不相信的东西上
But you can end your life based on something you don't believe?
但是你能就你不相信的东西结束你的生命吗?
What about love? I lived with you for years.
那么爱呢? 我和你生活了那么多年
I know you believe in love.
我知道你是相信爱的
Foreman wouldn't help me,
Foreman不肯帮我
which means I need you to take the fall.
这就意味着你得替我背黑锅了
You do remember I'm dying, right?
你还记得我快死了吧?
Which is you will never spend a day in jail.
所以你一天牢都不用坐
Fresh-faced, cancer-ridden.
年少无知 癌魔上身
It's tough to do both, but you pull it off. Your fingerprints are all over those hockey tickets.
- 两个都演挺困难 但你肯定能行的 - 那些冰球票上全是你的指纹
I never admitted to flushing anything.
我从来就没承认把什么东西冲下去过
My prints make sense if I gave those tickets to you as an incentive to stay alive.
如果我把那些票子送给你 作为让你活下去的动力 我的指纹就有解释了
And I was so angry that you didn't respect my dying wishes,
然后我因为你没有尊重我的意愿勃然大怒
I took thousands of dollars of season tickets and flushed them down toilets?
就拿了你几千块钱的票子 然后把它们冲进厕所下水道了?
All you have to do is create reasonable doubt.
你只需要制造合理疑点就可以了
Great, what if I do more than that? What if I end up in jail?
好极了 如果我不小心过戏了呢? 如果我被关进监狱了呢?
Or spending my final months in endless hearings?
或者 如果我剩下的五个月 都得在不停的听证会上度过了怎么办呢?
That is a risk you are willing to take.
这应该是你愿意冒的风险
I have a reputation. I have a legacy that could--
我还是有名誉在的好吗 我还想给世人留下...
Wilson...
Wilson...
I don't want to lose this time with you.
我不想失去和你在一起的最后时光
Okay.
好吧
Thanks.
谢谢
I knew I could count on you.
我就知道你是我可以依靠的人
Wait! Wait.
等等! 等一下
You want the fries back?
你想我把你的薯条吐出来?
I'm not gonna take the fall.
我不会为你背黑锅的
Don't do this to me, Wilson.
别这么对我啊 Wilson
This is our only option.
这是我们唯一的选择了
Exactly, because you overplayed your hand with Foreman,
没错 你和Foreman的这一手玩过了
because you knew you had me as a backstop.
就因为你老觉得我能替你担着
Even with me dying, you just assumed
哪怕我都快要死了 你也依然觉得
I'd be here to bail you out. Since you're here,
- 我会一直准备着把你保出来 - 你不是还在这儿
and you are bailing me out,
而且是要把我保出来嘛
seems like a pretty safe assumption.
这么想有什么错啊
I won't be here soon.
可我很快就不在了
If I do this, I'm teaching you that your bad behavior will always be rewarded.
如果我这么做了 我就是在告诉你 你的顽劣行为一直都会受到奖励
You need to learn-- How to act when you're gone?
- 你需要学着... - 在你死后怎么生活吗?
'Cause if that's the lesson, we got a really great opportunity coming up.
如果你想让我学这个 我们很快就有大好的机会了
You'll just try to find someone else, and it won't work, and it shouldn't work!
你只会去找人替代我 可你总是找不到 也本就不该找得到的!
So that's the great wisdom you're imparting?
于是这就是你想传达的大智慧了?
That I'll always be alone?
我会孤独终老吗?
There's only one person you can count on.
这世上只有一个人你可以依靠
I thought there were two.
我以为有两个呢
I need to do this...
我必须这么做...
for you.
我是为了你
Wilson's right. He's always right.
Wilson说得对 他永远都是对的
He's always been your good side.
他一直都是你好的那一面
I always wondered why I photographed so poorly.
我就说我照相老是那么难看
And because he's always played that role,
而且因为他一直扮演那个角色
you've never had to develop a conscience of your own.
你一直都没有培养出自己的良知
People don't change.
人是不会变的
Consciences don't spontaneously develop.
良知也是不能有意培养的
You're wrong, Greg.
你错了 Greg
Which is...
而这更说明...
why you'll be better off without him.
没有了他 你会活得更好
You've been looking to him
你总是依靠他来寻找
to find what you have gotta find within yourself.
你本应在自己身上找到的东西
Something you can find.
那些你本可以找到的东西
Hold your child.
抱抱你的孩子吧
This is a reason to die.
这是让我死的理由
This is what my life could've been, not what it can be.
这是我的生活可能成为的样子 而不是我想让它成为的样子
If it could've been,
如果曾有可能
you're capable of it now.
那现在你依然可以拥有
You're married. Cuddy's gone.
你结了婚 Cuddy离开了我
We aren't the only two people who could love you.
可我们俩并不是唯一能够爱上你的人
Why settle so easily?
为什么要这么容易就缴械投降呢?
These are just idiotic fantasies...
这些只是愚蠢的幻想...
Greg, don't.
Greg 别这样
At odds with every logical bone in my body.
与我身体中每一颗逻辑的骨头都是相悖的
Get up.
站起来
You do not have to die in here!
你不用死在这里的!
Is this hell?
已经到地狱了吗?
An eternity of people trying to convince me to live?
就这么永远不停有人来告诉我要活下去?
Who says I'm here to convince you to live?
谁说我是来叫你活下去的?
You're the last one I thought would hate me.
可你是我觉得最不可能恨我的人
I don't hate you.
我并不恨你
I love you.
我爱你
And yet you think I deserve to die.
而你却觉得我活该死吗
But not as a punishment.
但并不是作为惩罚而死呀
As a reward.
死亡是给你的奖赏
I think... you've suffered enough.
我觉得...你受的苦已经够多
You've given enough.
你的付出也已经够多
I think you deserve a chance to just...
我认为你应该有个机会...
give up.
就此放手
Like Wilson did? Like Wilson did.
- 就像Wilson一样? - 就像Wilson一样
You accepted his choice, that ending the pain
你接受了他的选择 结束痛苦
was better than the pain.
比痛苦要好许多
Why can't you give yourself that gift?
你为何不能也给自己这一份大礼呢?
This is the address House's patient gave?
这是House的病人留下的地址吗?
Everybody lies.
每个人都撒谎啊
You smell smoke?
你闻到烟味了吗?
Just let go.
放手吧
Just go to sleep.
只要长眠就好
I had a chance to avoid this.
我有机会避开这一切
You had many chances, and you blew them all up.
我有多少机会 却都被我挥霍殆尽
No, this was different.
不 这次是迥然不同的
They're all different, but the reasons are all the same.
它们都是迥然不同的 但背后的逻辑却一模一样
You're arrogant. You're self-destructive.
你心高气傲 带有自毁倾向
You only care about yourself.
而且只关心自己
That moment with the patient...
和病人在一起的那个时刻...
the chunk of the conversation I skipped over...
我跳过的那段对话...
I told him he was dying.
我告诉他 他要死了
If it makes you feel any better, at this rate, it'll be fast.
如果能让你感觉好点的话 以病情恶化的速度来看 你很快就会死的
Let me take the fall.
让我来替你背黑锅吧
For you, for that prank.
为你的那个恶作剧
You don't owe me anything.
可你并不欠我什么啊
- You tried to save me. - I failed.
- 你想要救我的命 - 但我失败了
Motives don't matter. Only actions.
动机并无用处 只有行动才算数
Trying is an action. Why are you trying to talk me out of this?
可尝试就是行动 你为什么要劝我别这么做呢?
You just fake the records.
只要伪造病历就可以了
You say I came into the clinic last week.
你可以说我上星期来过门诊
I'll tell the cops you treated me like crap,
我只要告诉警方你待我十分刻薄
so I stole your tickets and flushed 'em.
于是我就偷了你的球票把它们冲进了下水道
Thank you.
谢谢你
And you're doing this because you're dying?
你这么做只是因为你要死了吗?
I'm doing this because I have nothing left to lose.
我这么做是因为我已一无所有了
So when you were living, you did nothing for anyone
那就是说当你活着的时候 你没有为任何人做过任何事
and you didn't care. Now that you're dying,
也从不关心别人 而现在你要死了
you're willing to help a virtual stranger.
你却愿意帮助一个差不多完完全全的陌生人?
Which means you're a better person dying
那么就是说你在快死时
than you ever were living,
比你在生时是一个好得多的人
and the world is a better place
而这世界也因为
because I didn't save you.
我没有救活你而变得更美好了
Which makes me wonder why I'm about to tell you...
而这一切让我怀疑 我到底为什么要告诉你...
you're not symmetrical.
你的症状不是对称出现的
What's your point?
你这是何苦呢?
That you cared about him more than you cared about yourself?
你对他的关心比对自己的关心更甚吗?
You cared about the puzzle
你对谜题的关心
more than you cared about yourself.
比对自己的关心更甚
If I kept it to myself,
如果我闭口不语
then it would just be a puzzle,
这只会成为一个谜题
but I opened my mouth because I thought it was more.
但我说了出来 定是因为我觉得它的意义远胜于区区一个谜题
You know it's the same, or you wouldn't be bickering with me while the flames lick at your feet.
你知道这本无差别 以为当火舌缠绕住你的双脚 你就无法再跟我唇枪舌剑了
You're afraid of this decision, and you are trying to argue
你惧怕这个决定 而你现在的争论
until fate takes it out of your hands.
无非是在等命运把这结果从你手中夺去
You're taking the cowardly way out.
你选择了最懦弱的方式结束
And worse...
而更坏的是...
you're too cowardly to even admit you're taking the cowardly way out.
你懦弱到连自己选择懦弱的方式这点也不敢承认
You're right.
你说得对
But I can change.
但我还能改变
He could've gotten out.
他说不定出来了
People are found sometimes, even in...
有时候里面的人还是能找到的 哪怕在
collapsed--
已经倒塌的...
I think they're pulling a body out.
我觉得他们抬出来的是具尸体
Coroner confirms it's him.
验尸官确认了就是他
House hired me when no one else would.
House在没有人要我的时候雇了我
He got me fired.
他让我丢掉工作
He gave me the guts to get fired.
他给了我丢掉工作的决心
He gave me the courage to quit.
他给了我全身而退的勇气
Gregory was-- he was a good son.
Gregory是...他是我的好儿子
He was a trying boyfriend,
他是个棘手的男朋友
but I...
但我...
never stopped loving him.
对他的爱从未停止
He was my husband for real.
他是我货真价实的丈夫
I couldn't help but love him.
我情不自禁地爱上了他
He was my boss.
他是我的老板
And my employee.
也是我的手下
And both times...
而在这两个位置上...
I learned from him.
我都向他学到了很多
He made me a better parent,
他让我成为了更好的父亲
whether he meant to or not.
不管他原意是不是如此
He was willing to kill me.
他曾发誓会放手让我死
And I'll always be grateful.
而这点我会永远心怀感激
He wasn't always easy to deal with.
他一直都不是个好相处的人
But somewhere in there...
但在他内心深处...
he knew how to love.
他懂得如何去爱
He was my friend.
他是我的挚友
The thing you have to...
大家要...
remember--
记住的是...
the thing you can't forget is that Gregory House
大家一定不能忘记 Gregory House
saved lives.
精通治病救人之术
He was a healer.
医者仁心
And--and in the end...
而且 临到最后...
House was an ass.
House就是个混蛋
He mocked anyone--
他嘲笑所有人
patients, co-workers, his dwindling friends--
病人 同事 日渐衰弱的朋友--
anyone who didn't measure up to his insane ideals of integrity.
任何达不到他疯狂理想气节的人
He claimed to be on some heroic quest for truth,
他做出一副以英雄姿态寻找真理的架势
but the truth is, he was a bitter jerk who liked making people miserable.
但事实上 他只是个心怀怨毒 喜欢让别人觉得生活凄惨的混账
And he proved that by dying selfishly,
而他自私的死又是一大明证
numbed by narcotics, without a thought of anyone.
他用药物麻醉自己 从不考虑他人感受
A betrayal of everyone who cared about him.
这是对一切关心过他的人们的最大背叛
Phone.
电话关了好吗
A million times he needed me, and the one time that I needed him--
他无休止地需要我 而就这一次我需要他的时候
Oh, come on. This is a funeral.
哦 拜托你们好不好 这里是葬礼!
Just get it.
赶紧接起来算了吧
Well, this is embarrassing.
哎哟 这可真不好意思
Could've sworn I turned this off.
我明明记得我早就关机了呀
This isn't my phone.
这不是我的电话
SHUT UP YOU IDIOT
闭嘴吧 你个白痴
How?
怎么会...?
I got out of the back of the building.
我从后门跑出来了
The body--
可是那尸体--
Just switched the dental records.
只不过偷换了牙医记录而已
You're destroying your entire life.
可你这样是在毁掉你的一生
You can't go back from this.
这一去就再没有回头路了
You'll go to jail for years.
你会坐很多年的牢
You can never be a doctor again.
而且也再无法行医了
I'm dead, Wilson.
旧我已死 Wilson
How do you want to spend your last five months?
你想要如何度过 你最后的五个月呢?
* Shadows are falling *
* Shadows are falling *
* and I'm running out of breath *
* and I'm running out of breath *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* If I leave you, it doesn't mean I love you any less *
* If I leave you, it doesn't mean I love you any less *
* when you get up in the morning *
* when you get up in the morning *
* and you see that crazy sun *
* and you see that crazy sun *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* there's a train leaving nightly *
* there's a train leaving nightly *
* called when all is said and done *
* called when all is said and done *
* keep me your heart for a while *
* keep me your heart for a while *
* sha-la-la-la *
* sha-la-la-la *
* la-la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* la-la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* sha-la-la-la *
* sha-la-la-la *
* la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* sometimes when you're doin' *
* sometimes when you're doin' *
* simple things around the house *
* simple things around the house *
* maybe you'll think of me and smile *
* maybe you'll think of me and smile *
* you know I'm tied to you *
* you know I'm tied to you *
* like the buttons on your blouse *
* like the buttons on your blouse *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* sha-la-la-la *
* sha-la-la-la *
* la-la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* la-la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* sha-la-la-la *
* sha-la-la-la *
* la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* la-la-la-la-li-lo *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
* keep me in your heart for a while *
When the cancer starts getting really bad...
等到癌症开始严重恶化的时候...
Cancer's boring.
癌症多无聊
* Enjoy yourself *
* Enjoy yourself *
* it's later than you think *
* it's later than you think *
* enjoy yourself *
* enjoy yourself *
* while you're still in the pink *
* while you're still in the pink *
* the years go by *
* the years go by *
* as quickly as a wink *
* as quickly as a wink *
* enjoy yourself, enjoy yourself *
* enjoy yourself, enjoy yourself *
* it's later than you think, hey *
* it's later than you think, hey *
* you're gonna take that two-week trip *
* you're gonna take that two-week trip *
* no matter come what may *
* no matter come what may *
* but every year you put it off *
* but every year you put it off *
* you just can't get away *
* you just can't get away *
* next year for sure you'll hit the road *
* next year for sure you'll hit the road *
* you'll really get around *
* you'll really get around *
* but how far can you travel *
* but how far can you travel *
* when you're six feet underground? *
* when you're six feet underground? *
* enjoy yourself *
* enjoy yourself *
* it's later than you think *
* it's later than you think *
* while you're still in the pink *
* while you're still in the pink *
* the years go by as quickly as a wink *
* the years go by as quickly as a wink *
* enjoy yourself, enjoy yourself *
* enjoy yourself, enjoy yourself *
* it's later than you think *
* it's later than you think *
* enjoy yourself *
* enjoy yourself *
* don't be a fool *
* don't be a fool *
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入
破烂熊字幕组 -==http://www.ragbear.com==- 欢迎加入